propertygenie.co.za 2014-06-25

# PropertyGenie

_Last updated: April 2014_

Factory (PTY) LTD owns and operates PropertyGenie - a South African property listing website (http://www.propertygenie.co.za) that is governed by the Privacy Policy Statement described below as well as the PropertyGenie Terms and Conditions Statement. 

PropertyGenie reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to amend and/or replace any of, or the whole of, the Terms. Such amendments shall supersede and replace any previous Terms and shall be made available on the Website. Each time you access the Website, you are deemed to have consented, by such access, to the Terms, as amended and/or replaced by PropertyGenie from time to time. 

By using any part of the Website or by clicking a box that states that you accept or agree to those Terms, you signify your agreement to these terms. If you do not agree to these Terms, you may not use the Website. 

In the event of a dispute as to the content of the Terms at any time, a certificate signed by the administrator responsible for maintaining the Website shall be prima facie proof of the date of publication and content of the current version and all previous versions of the Terms. 

####  Your Privacy 

PropertyGenie is 100% committed to protecting your privacy. PropertyGenie uses the information collected to enable you to search and enquire about property listed on the PropertyGenie website, to provide support for our product and - with your express consent - to support sponsor promotions and market research. 

#### What information does PropertyGenie collect and how is this information used? 

When you request to be contacted by an agent, we ask for your name, email address, and mobile number in order for them to contact you. We forward this information onto our partners and estate agents and also store such information on our side in order for the agent to be able to retrieve these details. We use these email addresses to send out information we believe relevant to you. You can unsubscribe at any time from these newsletters by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the mail. Please see our unsubscribe and contact us section below for further details. 

Only if you consent to sharing information with us and/or our partners by providing these details, and requesting contact, may we and/or our partners use this information to provide you with product or service related offers, and/or only if you consent to hearing from us and/or our partners can they aggregate the information for the purposes of market research. Information is only sent to a partner and/or third party should you consent to this. 

Other than in respect of personal information, if you provide information to PropertyGenie, you agree that such information is not confidential information and that PropertyGenie has unlimited rights to such information and that PropertyGenie may use such information at its discretion. 

While using the Website, information about you may be either collected by us or provided by you, such as, without limitation, your name, surname, title, birth date, identification number, gender, country of residence, closest city, address, contact numbers, non-personal browsing habits and click patterns, email address and IP address. You consent to such collection of information. 

You agree that PropertyGenie may collate, process, use and store the information referred to above to greet you when you log onto the Website, inform you of facts relating to your access and use of the Website, provide you with periodic information regarding products, services, competitions, special offers and other marketing initiatives of PropertyGenie, its partners or affiliates and/or other third parties ("Marketing Initiatives"), to communicate with you, and request information from you and to compile non-personal statistical information about browsing habits, click-patterns and access to the Website. 

If sells its business or part of it, it will share the information about you, which it has collected from your use of the Website, with the purchaser, who may then provide you with information about their products, services and marketing initiatives only on the same conditions as you have agreed to here. Should you wish to unsubscribe please contact us at support@propertygenie.co.za. 

You acknowledge and agree that by creating customer profile and uploading and sharing such customer profile, for example on websites dedicated to discussion forums, such information is not confidential. 

PropertyGenie may collect, maintain, save, compile, share, disclose any information collected from you, subject to the following provisions: 

PropertyGenie not disclose any personal information to anyone except as provided for in these Terms; 

PropertyGenie may compile, use and share any information that is not personal information for statistical and research purposes; 

PropertyGenie may disclose personal information to its employees and agents who require such information to carry out their duties or any activity incidental thereto; and 

PropertyGenie shall disclose personal information where the law requires it to disclose such personal information. 

In all other situations, PropertyGenie shall not disclose personal information without giving you prior notice thereof and an opportunity for you to consent thereto. 

Where disclosure has been made to any third party, PropertyGenie undertakes to keep records of such third party disclosure, in accordance with section 51 of the Electronic Communications and Transactions Act 25 of 2002. 

You agree and recognise that information provided may be susceptible to the provisions of the Regulation of Interception of Communications Act 70 of 2002. As such, PropertyGenie may possess the right to intercept, read, monitor, block, delete, and/or close the information provided to the Website. 

Option to discontinue services or direct communication from us. See unsubscribe section below for further details on how to unsubscribe and/or contact us. 

Will PropertyGenie disclose the information it collects to third parties? 

In order to be contacted by a Partner/ estate agent you will request for them to contact you on the PropertyGenie wesbite. By submitting such information, you give permission for PropertyGenie to share your information with that Partner/ estate agent in order for the Partner/ estate agent to contact you or send you an offer: information about products and/or services that may be of interest to you. 

PropertyGenie does not maintain the materials that can be accessed from linked sites and PropertyGenie is not responsible for the contents thereof. Any reference to a linked site or any specific third party product or service by name does not constitute or imply its endorsement by PropertyGenie, and you assume all risk with respect to its use 

How does PropertyGenie protect member information? 

A Secure Server for collecting personal information is used. These servers sit in the UK purely for server quality and protection offered. By accepting the privacy policy you agree to your information being stored in a foreign country. The secure server layer [SSL] encrypts all the information you enter before it's transmitted over the internet and sent to us. Furthermore, all of the member data we collect is protected against unauthorised access. 

PropertyGenie has taken reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of information provided by you, but does not make any representations or warranties that the information provided by you, whether personal information, or otherwise, is absolutely safe and secure. 

What about cookies? 

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Whenever you log in to PropertyGenie we store your unique ID [not your SA ID] and the time you signed in, in an encrypted session cookie on your hard drive. When you log out of PropertyGenie, these session cookies expire. The functionality of PropertyGenie depends upon your browser accepting session cookies. 

PropertyGenie tracks visitors to and on the website by using referrer tracking and uses click through and open mail tracking when sending emails. 

Your Consent 

By using the PropertyGenie website (http://www.PropertyGenie.co.za/)), you consent to the collection and use of the information as described above by PropertyGenie. If any changes are made to this privacy policy, an update will be displayed on the website, so that you are always aware of what information is collected, how it is used, and under what circumstances it is disclosed. The "last updated" date at the top and bottom of the Privacy Statement will be revised should any update occur. 

####  External Sites and Emails 

PropertyGenie provides links to other sites from our website and our emails. The privacy policies of these linked sites are the responsibility of the linked site and PropertyGenie has no control or influence over their policies. Please check the policies of each site you visit for specific information. PropertyGenie cannot be held liable for damage or misdoings of other sites linked or otherwise. 

####  Security 

Whilst PropertyGenie has taken reasonable measures to ensure the integrity of this Website and their contents, no warranty, whether express or implied, is given that any files, downloads or applications available via this Website are free of viruses, Trojans, time bombs, time-locks, phishing programmes or other harmful programs. 

You acknowledge that because information is transmitted via the Internet, such information, irrespective of whether it constitutes personal information, may be susceptible to monitoring and interception. Accordingly, you are discouraged from transmitting to the Website any information that may be viewed as confidential and/or of a sensitive nature and you bear all the risk of transmitting information in this manner. Under no circumstances shall PropertyGenie be liable for any loss, harm, or damage suffered by you as a result thereof. 

PropertyGenie hereby reserves the right to take whatever action it finds necessary to preserve the security, integrity and reliability of its network and back-office applications. 

You may not utilise Website in any manner which may compromise the security of the Website in any manner whatsoever, which shall include without limitation, delivering or attempting to deliver any unauthorised, damaging or malicious code to the Website, which is expressly prohibited. 

Any user who commits any of the offences detailed in Chapter 13 of the Electronic Communications and Transaction Act 25 of 2005 (specifically sections 85 to 89 (inclusive)) shall, notwithstanding criminal prosecution, be liable for all resulting liability, loss or damages suffered and/or incurred by PropertyGenie and its affiliates, agents and/or partners. 

####  Contact Information and unsubscribe 

Should you at any point wish to unsubscribe from our services or discontinue direct communication please e-mail us on [support@propertygenie.co.za](mailto:support@propertygenie.co.za). To unsubscribe from a newsletter simply click the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email and you will be unsubscribed automatically from receiving these newsletters. 

Should you wish you contact us please do so at support@propertygenie.co.za 

Last updated: 2014
